<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Dan Collis-Puro]]></title>
  <link href="http://cpblog.herokuapp.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://cpblog.herokuapp.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-08-27T10:01:23-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://cpblog.herokuapp.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[djcp]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to get good repair service from SprintPCS]]></title>
    <link href="http://cpblog.herokuapp.com/blog/2012/08/27/how-to-get-good-support-from-sprint/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-27T09:48:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://cpblog.herokuapp.com/blog/2012/08/27/how-to-get-good-support-from-sprint</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Don&#8217;t go to a non-corporate store.  The resellers just don&#8217;t seem to care about customers as much as the employees at the corporate stores.</p>

<p>I have been lied to (directly!), gotten repeated lame excuses (You JUST missed our tech!) and generally had clueless service.  It&#8217;s farther and much more annoying to get to a corporate store for me, but the time and frustration saved is worth it. Lessons learned.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wrap-up of my first week at thoughtbot]]></title>
    <link href="http://cpblog.herokuapp.com/blog/2012/08/18/wrap-up-of-my-first-week-at-thoughtbot/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-18T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://cpblog.herokuapp.com/blog/2012/08/18/wrap-up-of-my-first-week-at-thoughtbot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Random thoughts about my first week as a developer at thoughtbot:</p>

<ul>
<li>I have much to learn about design patterns. The <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Design_Patterns">GoF book</a> will be my close friend for a while.</li>
    <li>I know more about metaprogramming than I thought, I just needed the terminology.</li>
    <li>Pairing is an amazing way to transfer knowledge and should be done frequently. I learned a ton during and after because I took notes and then researched and practiced concepts new to me.</li>
    <li>thoughtbot invests a huge amount of time (and therefore money) improving the skills of its developers. It shows.</li>
    <li>osx is a fine desktop environment, but the amount of crap you need to wade through to set it up as a ruby development environment (as compared to debian / ubuntu) is kind of hilarious. That said, it&#8217;s working fine now and it wasn&#8217;t particularly hard, it just didn&#8217;t feel &#8220;native&#8221; like it does on linux.  I could take or leave osx, but it&#8217;d be hard to stop using a retina display - text is absolutely gorgeous.</li>
    <li>I don&#8217;t know what I&#8217;d do without <a href="http://mxcl.github.com/homebrew/">homebrew</a>.</li>
    <li>thoughtbot <a href="https://github.com/thoughtbot/dotfiles">dotfiles</a> are great, and the vim set up was very similar to my own but with significant additional refinements. Use them.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
