<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Dan Collis-Puro]]></title>
  <link href="http://cpblog.herokuapp.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://cpblog.herokuapp.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-08-19T22:53:23-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://cpblog.herokuapp.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[djcp]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A new octopress blog]]></title>
    <link href="http://cpblog.herokuapp.com/blog/2012/08/19/new-post/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-19T22:24:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://cpblog.herokuapp.com/blog/2012/08/19/new-post</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>How droll. A new octopress blog published to heroku.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wrap-up of my first week at thoughtbot]]></title>
    <link href="http://cpblog.herokuapp.com/blog/2012/08/18/wrap-up-of-my-first-week-at-thoughtbot/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-18T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://cpblog.herokuapp.com/blog/2012/08/18/wrap-up-of-my-first-week-at-thoughtbot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Random thoughts about my first week as a developer at thoughtbot:</p>

<ul>
<li>I have much to learn about design patterns. The <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Design_Patterns">GoF book</a> will be my close friend for a while.</li>
    <li>I know more about metaprogramming than I thought, I just needed the terminology.</li>
    <li>Pairing is an amazing way to transfer knowledge and should be done frequently. I learned a ton during and after because I took notes and then researched and practiced concepts new to me.</li>
    <li>thoughtbot invests a huge amount of time (and therefore money) improving the skills of its developers. It shows.</li>
    <li>osx is a fine desktop environment, but the amount of crap you need to wade through to set it up as a ruby development environment (as compared to debian / ubuntu) is kind of hilarious. That said, it&#8217;s working fine now and it wasn&#8217;t particularly hard, it just didn&#8217;t feel &#8220;native&#8221; like it does on linux.  I could take or leave osx, but it&#8217;d be hard to stop using a retina display - text is absolutely gorgeous.</li>
    <li>I don&#8217;t know what I&#8217;d do without <a href="http://mxcl.github.com/homebrew/">homebrew</a>.</li>
    <li>thoughtbot <a href="https://github.com/thoughtbot/dotfiles">dotfiles</a> are great, and the vim set up was very similar to my own but with significant additional refinements. Use them.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[S3:E17 - Sins of the Father]]></title>
    <link href="http://cpblog.herokuapp.com/blog/2012/07/30/s3e17-sins-of-the-father/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-30T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://cpblog.herokuapp.com/blog/2012/07/30/s3e17-sins-of-the-father</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>This is the one with Warf&#8217;s brother. Everyone thinks that Warf&#8217;s father betrayed the Klingon people. Warf lost because the Klingon Commander was hiding that the other mean Klingon&#8217;s father was the traitor.  Warf isn&#8217;t a Klingon any more, I bet that was probably hard because he can&#8217;t go back to his home planet again.</blockquote>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[S3:E16 - The Offspring]]></title>
    <link href="http://cpblog.herokuapp.com/blog/2012/07/30/s3e16-the-offspring/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-30T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://cpblog.herokuapp.com/blog/2012/07/30/s3e16-the-offspring</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>This was a very sad episode, poor Data! His daughter died, I don&#8217;t get why they turned her off, what&#8217;s wrong with having emotions? The Star Fleet guy was like &#8220;It&#8217;s just a machine, it doesn&#8217;t have proper surroundings to learn stuff.&#8221;  She was malfunctioning and started to have emotions, he made her too good - and she used a contraction.</blockquote>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[S3:18 - Allegiance]]></title>
    <link href="http://cpblog.herokuapp.com/blog/2012/07/30/s318-allegiance/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-30T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://cpblog.herokuapp.com/blog/2012/07/30/s318-allegiance</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>Some annoying aliens kidnapped Picard, and he was smart. There was some annoying alien that thought they shouldn&#8217;t do anything, along with a crazy monster. There was also a Starfleet cadet that knew too much, and she turned out to be the meanie alien. They taught the aliens that they shouldn&#8217;t capture people after containing them in a purple containment circle thing. It was fine, nothing exciting. At the end it was funny because Dr. Crusher was looking funny at Picard.</blockquote>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Google Nexus 7 16gb mini-review]]></title>
    <link href="http://cpblog.herokuapp.com/blog/2012/07/29/google-nexus-7-16gb-mini-review/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-29T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://cpblog.herokuapp.com/blog/2012/07/29/google-nexus-7-16gb-mini-review</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My thoughts on the 16gb Google nexus 7 tablet after a few days using it - the short version: I love it. Buy one.</p>

<p><strong>PROS:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Fast.</li>
    <li>3d performance is amazingly good.</li>
    <li>High build quality and it feels great in your hands.</li>
    <li>Great battery life.</li>
    <li>Gorgeous screen.</li>
    <li>Jellybean is a pleasure and evolutionary in all the right places.  I&#8217;ve not used ICS on a device I own so I admit some ignorance on when these improvements came to be.
<ul>
<li>The email client is VASTLY improved.</li>
    <li>The calendar is SO much better than it was in gingerbread.</li>
    <li>Mobile chrome kicks ass.</li>
    <li>App switching, notifications, home screen shortcut features, the list goes on for improvements since gingerbread.</li>
    <li>Jellybean netflix client (and many other apps) have pretty great feature improvements compared to their gingerbread counterparts.</li>
</ul>
</li>
    <li>It is trivial to open the device and do basic consumer-level repairs. You can replace the battery! I would imagine we&#8217;ll see aftermarket extended batteries soon.</li>
    <li>Comfortable form factor.</li>
    <li>Price - $250 with a $25 google play credit.</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>CONS:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>No sdcard slot.</li>
    <li>No flash support. I know, flash sucks, but some sites that render perfectly in mobile chrome lack features (games, video) because there&#8217;s no flash.</li>
    <li>The built-in video player loses time sync sometimes, so it &#8220;forgets&#8221; where it is in a video it&#8217;s playing. I&#8217;m sure this&#8217;ll get resolved in a forthcoming update.</li>
    <li>Lack of rear facing camera makes it slightly less &#8220;social.&#8221;</li>
    <li>Not unlocked by default (but trivial to unlock manually).</li>
    <li>I don&#8217;t like that the power button and volume rockers are on the same side, it&#8217;s easy to mistake them and turn off the device accidentally. This will go away as the device controls work their way into muscle memory.</li>
    <li>No video out.</li>
    <li>It takes a long time to charge, but it does have a pretty large battery.</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>RANDOM:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>The GPS is very accurate and quick, but it&#8217;s not incredibly useful given the device is wifi-only. I&#8217;ve been wifi tethering it to my phone (thanks <a href="http://cyanogenmod.com">cyanogenmod</a>!) and it makes a lot more sense to have an always-on connection.</li>
    <li>This could be because I&#8217;m used to having screen protectors on my devices, but the touchscreen seems to be more sensitive and to have better &#8220;swipe-feel&#8221; after putting a skinomi screen protector on it.</li>
    <li>The device is a portal to google&#8217;s services and would be far less useful without a google account.</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>CONCLUSION:</strong></p>

<p>Honestly, I love it. 95 out of 100 - the cons are far outweighed by the pros especially in light of the price. I think this device will have a long, happy life in my tech arsenal.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[S3:E9 - The Vengeance Factor]]></title>
    <link href="http://cpblog.herokuapp.com/blog/2012/07/11/s3e9-the-vengeance-factor/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-11T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://cpblog.herokuapp.com/blog/2012/07/11/s3e9-the-vengeance-factor</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>Utah was like an ancient person that was genetically altered so she could kill all of a clan that had destroyed her clan. Riker got all kissy-kissy with her but she didn&#8217;t have any emotions.  Riker shot her with his phaser.</blockquote>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[S3:E8 - The Price]]></title>
    <link href="http://cpblog.herokuapp.com/blog/2012/07/11/s3e8-the-price/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-11T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://cpblog.herokuapp.com/blog/2012/07/11/s3e8-the-price</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>Troi gets all lovey with one of the negotiators and he asks her to run away. I think the negotiation was just a background for the lovey part. Riker set the guy in his place and told him to go away, &#8220;Troi deserves better than you&#8221; or something. The negotiator was an empath like Troi. He was hot though.</blockquote>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[S3:E7 - The Enemy]]></title>
    <link href="http://cpblog.herokuapp.com/blog/2012/07/11/s3e7-the-enemy/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-11T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://cpblog.herokuapp.com/blog/2012/07/11/s3e7-the-enemy</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>This one was the LaForge episode. I like LaForge a lot, so this was a good episode. The radiation was messing up the Romulan, and LaForge couldn&#8217;t see any more because his, what is it called?, visor wasn&#8217;t working. No, his connection with the visor was messed up. They had to work together to make a thing to find the orb thing the Enterprise sent down and to change it to signal. Pretty good one.</blockquote>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[S3:E6 - Booby Trap]]></title>
    <link href="http://cpblog.herokuapp.com/blog/2012/07/11/s3e6-booby-trap/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-11T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://cpblog.herokuapp.com/blog/2012/07/11/s3e6-booby-trap</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>It wasn&#8217;t very interesting, some radiation that was on some speary things that was messing up the Enterprise&#8217;s computer. They couldn&#8217;t control the engines any more, like the other ship that was like 5000 years old. I don&#8217;t even remember how they fixed it.</blockquote>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[S3:E15 - Yesterday's Enterprise]]></title>
    <link href="http://cpblog.herokuapp.com/blog/2012/07/11/s3e15-yesterdays-enterprise/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-11T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://cpblog.herokuapp.com/blog/2012/07/11/s3e15-yesterdays-enterprise</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>This one was sort of confusing because I didn&#8217;t know why the ship changed, but then Daddy explained it to me. So the Enterprise had changed and was still at war with the Klingons because 22 years ago some ship didn&#8217;t save a Klingon base so the war continued. Yar was still alive! Yar went on to the older ship and umm I don&#8217;t know. I forget. She kissed one of the guys that was 22 years older than her, sort of weird. He shouldn&#8217;t been like 50 something, she was kissing an ancient person. Our Enterprise was darker, different uniforms, stuff like that. There was no Worf or Troi, poor Troi. I liked that episode a lot.</blockquote>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[S3:E14 - A Matter of Perception]]></title>
    <link href="http://cpblog.herokuapp.com/blog/2012/07/11/s3e14-a-matter-of-perception/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-11T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://cpblog.herokuapp.com/blog/2012/07/11/s3e14-a-matter-of-perception</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>The starbase that Riker was going to to check out something waves exploded after he left. The scientist guy&#8217;s wife? and his assistant accused Riker of exploding the base. It was actually the scientist because he didn&#8217;t like Riker. I don&#8217;t need to add anything else, I don&#8217;t want to talk about this episode.</blockquote>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[S3:E13 - Deja Q]]></title>
    <link href="http://cpblog.herokuapp.com/blog/2012/07/11/s3e13-deja-q/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-11T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://cpblog.herokuapp.com/blog/2012/07/11/s3e13-deja-q</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>That&#8217;s a funny name - &#8220;Deja Q.&#8221; So Q comes along again and says he lost all his powers. He&#8217;s really confused, he doesn&#8217;t know how to eat, he gets back pains, he thinks he can order people around. He&#8217;s pretty funny. Some aliens that didn&#8217;t like Q because he tormented them came along and were zapping him, destroying the ship. Q went out into a shuttle and aliens attacked him, but then another Q guy came along and gave Q back his powers because he said he was improving because of his selfless act. It was really funny because they were remarking at each other.</blockquote>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[S3:E12 - The High Ground]]></title>
    <link href="http://cpblog.herokuapp.com/blog/2012/07/11/s3e12-the-high-ground/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-11T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://cpblog.herokuapp.com/blog/2012/07/11/s3e12-the-high-ground</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>It&#8217;s always with these rebel guys, these episodes. Crusher gets captured, these rebels are using teleportation thing that messes up their health. The leader wants Dr. Crusher to help them, but she says she can&#8217;t and gets mad at him. The rebel captures Picard and is going to kill him, then they find the spot and saves everybody. I liked that episode.</blockquote>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[S3:E11 - The Hunted]]></title>
    <link href="http://cpblog.herokuapp.com/blog/2012/07/11/s3e11-the-hunted/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-11T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://cpblog.herokuapp.com/blog/2012/07/11/s3e11-the-hunted</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>That guy who had extreme strength, he&#8217;d been genetically altered. His instincts would kick in whenever he was in danger, flipping full grown men in the air. Then Troi was being friendly with the man and he didn&#8217;t like it. The Enterprise just said &#8220;Bye-bye. Your problem!&#8221; when the soldier guy got back on the planet.</blockquote>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[S3:E10 - The Defector]]></title>
    <link href="http://cpblog.herokuapp.com/blog/2012/07/11/s3e10-the-defector/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-11T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://cpblog.herokuapp.com/blog/2012/07/11/s3e10-the-defector</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>Right, the Romulan guy was set up with fake information. He came rushing to the Federation, to Picard and was like &#8220;OMG! Some evil Romulans are going to come destroy you on some planet.&#8221; Then suddenly they figured out he&#8217;d been given wrong information and it was just to test his loyalty, and he failed horribly.</blockquote>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[S3:E5 - The Bonding]]></title>
    <link href="http://cpblog.herokuapp.com/blog/2012/07/03/s3e5-the-bonding/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-03T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://cpblog.herokuapp.com/blog/2012/07/03/s3e5-the-bonding</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>Well, a crew member dies and she leaves her son behind. Then some person pretends to be his mother and changes the room to look like their home on Earth.  And then Worf does the weird Klingon ceremony and they both become brothers because they are both orphans. Worf actually starts to show a bit of emotion. Good episode, cute kid.</blockquote>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[S3:E4 - Who Watches the Watchers]]></title>
    <link href="http://cpblog.herokuapp.com/blog/2012/07/03/s3e4-who-watches-the-watchers/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-03T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://cpblog.herokuapp.com/blog/2012/07/03/s3e4-who-watches-the-watchers</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>So this one had a lot about Vulcans. First time we met Vulcans.  There were some Vulcans that were worshipping Captain Picard because they thought he could bring them back from the dead. Troi and Riker went down and the Vulcans wanted to sacrifice them. Then Riker got away with one of the injured people from the lab explosion but Troi was left behind and they almost sacrificed her. Then they shot Captain Picard and he almost died. I like Vulcans, they brought the Vulcan leader onto the ship and persuaded her that they were all the same and that some day they would have the same powers.</blockquote>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[S3:E3 - The Survivors]]></title>
    <link href="http://cpblog.herokuapp.com/blog/2012/07/03/s3e3-the-survivors/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-03T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://cpblog.herokuapp.com/blog/2012/07/03/s3e3-the-survivors</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>I didn&#8217;t like this one because it made Troi have a song stuck in her head. There was a guy and everyone else had been destroyed, he had his wife and later they figured out that he was a powerful being and he had created everything. He was making the song in Troi&#8217;s head so she couldn&#8217;t figure out the truth. I liked it besides poor Troi who had stuff stuck in her head.</blockquote>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[S3:E2 - The Ensigns of Command]]></title>
    <link href="http://cpblog.herokuapp.com/blog/2012/07/03/s3e2-the-ensigns-of-command/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-03T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://cpblog.herokuapp.com/blog/2012/07/03/s3e2-the-ensigns-of-command</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>This one was really weird. The Shelliac wanted the human colony to get off and there was a stubborn human guy that wouldn&#8217;t leave the planet. The Shelliac were going to destroy them but they finally went away. Data was trying to persuade them and he made a -~*girlfriend*~-. I like this episode a lot, because of the girl. She was really smart and cool, and Data made a -~*girlfriend*~-.</blockquote>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
